<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Self Improvement on Lamin Sanneh</title><link>http://laminsanneh.com/categories/self-improvement/</link><description>Recent content in Self Improvement on Lamin Sanneh</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2013 09:10:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://laminsanneh.com/categories/self-improvement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What is Technical Debt?</title><link>http://laminsanneh.com/posts/technical-debt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2013 09:10:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://laminsanneh.com/posts/technical-debt/</guid><description>Introduction As someone who crunches out code, whether moderately or a lot if you’re like me. You must have incurred some technical debt somewhere along the lines.
Development approaches Technical debt is the term given to a certain programming scenario. Assume you had a project with a target deadline. As the technical lead of the project, you are sometimes faced with two decisions which are:
The long and proper way Using this approach is the most ideal way of development.</description></item><item><title>Staying Sane among all the craziness (keeping up with technology)</title><link>http://laminsanneh.com/posts/staying-sane-craziness-keeping-technology/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2013 09:07:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://laminsanneh.com/posts/staying-sane-craziness-keeping-technology/</guid><description>A wiseman’s advice My dad once told me boy. Yes, literally, “boy” was the nickname he gave me for some reason. He said “you will never be satisfied if you always want to keep up with the latest and greatest gadgets”. He also said that sometimes its ok to be behind schedule a little bit. You see, my thought as a young, gadget addicted teenager was that. “This was some excuse he’d come up with just to have some breathing space from getting me the latest video games”.</description></item><item><title>How learning a new programming language can help you become a better programmer?</title><link>http://laminsanneh.com/posts/learning-programming-language-programmer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2013 09:20:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://laminsanneh.com/posts/learning-programming-language-programmer/</guid><description>My Theory I came into first year at the University of Manchester, with a fair knowledge of programming in Java. I was fully aware that there were people out there who were well versed in other languages and using it to solve real life problems. Even with this knowledge, I did not even bother to look into any other because I hadn’t yet known the importance of learning a new programming language.</description></item></channel></rss>